I am a dedicated senior software engineer with a unique set of technical and management skills. As a technical leader, I have the ability to gather and understand business requirements, translate them into a solution design and oversee the technical direction of a project. In my project management capacity, I am used to dividing the development work into sensible, deliverable chunks, writing techfriendly tickets, delegating them to the team (including myself) and keeping stakeholders up to date. From process management point of view, I keep an eye on development processes focusing on efficiency and simplicity, contributing with some improvement ideas where needed. I also have experience in line management and recruitment.

Skills

Technical skills:

- OO Languages C#, Java, Delphi, Visual Basic
- Scripting languages Javascript, Bash, Powershell
- Databases MS SQL Server, Couchbase, MySQL
- Frameworks .NET Core, .NET Framework, MVC, Web API, React+Redux, WCF
- Testing nUnit, Postman, SoapUI, Jest, Cypress
- Other Git, SVN, JIRA, TeamCity, Octopus Deploy, GoCD, Docker, Kubernetes, Helm, Azure, AWS

Soft skills:

Motivated, self-driven, great communication skills, comfortable with intercultural team work, project and process management skills, ability to work against tight deadlines, line management, recruitment

Languages:

- Polish native
- English fluent
- German business proficient
- Spanish business proficient

Work Experience

11.2018 – onwards: Senior Software Engineer at leso, Cambridge, England

Technical leadership, solution design, implementing infrastructural and process improvements, development. Main projects:

- Financial eligibility and registration flow,
- Admin portal

Technologies used: C#, ASP.NET Core, React + Redux, Jest, Cypress, SQL Server, Docker, Kubernetes, GoCD, Helm, Azure

09.2016 - 10.2018: Principal Engineer at Bango, Cambridge, England

Main duties: solution design, improving code quality across the team, managing and improving sprint delivery process (Scrum), development. Other duties: release management (TeamCity + Octopus Deploy) and business critical issues investigation (including production environment), line management. Main projects:

- Financial reconciliation and remittance system,
- Bango International Proxy service

Technologies used: C#, ASP.NET Web API, WCF, React + Redux, SQL Server, Couchbase Server Trainings completed: Creating Software Architectures, Docker

02.2015 - 09.2016: Systems Developer at Bango, Cambridge, England

Designing, developing and maintaining systems behind the world's leading mobile payments platform used by Amazon, Google, Microsoft and many more. Main projects:

- Bango API REST service for app stores to integrate with,
- Identification engine functionality performing app store's user identification,
- NoSQL transaction layer library exposing functionality to perform atomic transactions in non-transactional NoSQL environment (Couchbase)

Technologies used: C#, MVC, Web API, SQL Server, Couchbase Server

Trainings completed: Web App Security, MVC, Asynchronous Programming in C# 5

09.2014 - 02.2015: IT Graduate Trainee at Cambridge Assessment, University of Cambridge, England

Training covering a variety of areas within IT field, including Business Analysis team, SAP team and Enterprise Application Integrations team (main placement).

Technologies used: Biztalk, SQL Server, C#, XSD, XSLT.

Trainings completed: Biztalk 2013, Powerful Presentations, Effective Teamwork, Negotiation Skills.

02.2013 - 08.2014: Software Developer at Informica, Grodzisk Mazowiecki, Poland

Design and development of multi-threaded, database-oriented applications for bus carrier companies.

Technologies used: Delphi, SQL Server, JavaScript, IIS, Google Maps API.

Successfully completed Querying Microsoft SQL Server 2012 course, MCP certificate (11.2013)

10.2012 - 11.2012: Intern at Ultra Computing, Skopje, Macedonia

Developing a web application to perform basic CRUD operations on data.

Technologies used: Java, JSP, Hibernate, MySQL.

07.2012 – 09.2012: Intern at Effective Soft, Minsk, Belarus

Developing a photo editing tool, designing a website.

Technologies used: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, VB.

Education

02.2011 – 01.2013: AGH University of Science and Technology, Krakow, Poland

Master's degree in Geoinformatics

09.2007 – 02.2011: AGH University of Science and Technology, Krakow, Poland

Engineer's degree in Geodesy and Cartography

Personal achievements

2006 – **2010**: Summer job as a cycling trips tour leader. Job involved leading international groups, performing organisational tasks and providing cultural background in German, English and Spanish.

1994 – 2005: Music education. As a drummer I performed live many times with bands, which contributed greatly to my self-confidence. I still pursue drumming as a hobby.

Interests

Music, outdoor sports (cycling, snowboarding, scuba diving), movies

Personal details

Full name:	Michal Ciesielski
Address:	Cambridge, England
Phone number:	+44 7761 363301
E-mail:	michal.a.ciesielski@gmail.com